LONG PHI HOANG

Work Water Systems and Global Change Group,

Wageningen University, the Netherlands

Mobile + 31 62 246 2599 **Date of Birth** 20/02/1987

Email Long.hoang@wur.nl

Add. 1 Pluvierplein 9-1 1022AS Amsterdam, the Netherlands Add 2. 45/123 Xuan Thuy Street, Cau Giay, Hanoi, Vietnam

Profiles Linkedin | Google Scholar | Research Gates | Wageningen University

CURRENT POSITIONS

Postdoc researcher on Water Resources Management and Climate Change. Water Systems and Global Change Group, Wageningen University, the Netherlands

Founder of New Amsterdam Consult - Start-up Company for Science, Education and Technology exchanges between the Dutch and Asian markets.

SUMMARY

Dr. Long Phi Hoang is a multidisciplinary researcher who works in, and across the fields of water management; climate change; and science-technology-innovation exchanges. His work focuses on, but not limited to, climate change impacts on water resources, sustainable food production, and ICT innovations for climate change adaptation. His research focuses strongly on several large river deltas of the world, including the Dutch, Vietnamese, Bangladeshi and Ghanaian deltas. Dr. Hoang is involved in various training and education activities at Wageningen University. He is active in several science-policy dialogues and science-driven decision making projects, including the high-level Dutch-Vietnamese strategic collaboration to develop the Mekong Delta Plan, and the consultancy project for the European Commission. In 2019, Dr. Hoang establishes his start-up (New Amsterdam Consult), focusing on Science, Education and Technology transfer between the Netherlands, Vietnam and beyond.

EDUCATION PROFILE

PhD in Hydrology and Earth System Science (2013-2017)

SENSE Research School, Wageningen University, the Netherlands

Master of Environmental Sciences (2009-2011, Cum Laude, top 3%)

Water Management and Climate Change, Wageningen University, the Netherlands

Bachelor of Environmental Management (2005-2009, with Distinction, top 1%)

Hanoi National University, Hanoi, Vietnam

EXPERTISE

River delta system: Strategic delta planning and management, hydrological processes.

Water resources management: Hydrological modelling, Integrated water management and strategic planning.

Climate change: Climate change, climate impacts and risks, adaptation. **Academic consultancy:** Consulting and advisory service for businesses.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

2019 - now: Founder of New Amsterdam Consult for Science, Education and Technology transfer, Vietnam and the Netherlands.

Jan 2017 - now: Postdoc researcher on water information services (<u>Waterapps</u>) for sustainable food production in peri-urban delta regions, Water System and Global Change group, Wageningen University, the Netherlands.

Jan 2013-Arpil 2017: PhD researcher: *Hydrological changes in the Mekong River basin under climate change: Modelling the changes and exploring adaptation options.* SENSE Research School, Wageningen University, the Netherlands.

2015: Researcher in collaboration with the University of Amsterdam, evaluating the ecological and economic benefits of the national program for Payment for Ecosystem Services (PES) in Vietnam.

2012: Research associate, start up the <u>Water Futures and Solutions</u> project, International Institute for Applied System Analysis (IIASA), Laxenburg, Austria.

2011-2012: Researcher, develop scenarios and adaptation strategies in the *Mekong Delta Plan* – High level collaborative project between the Netherlands & Vietnam.

2010-2011: Junior Researcher <u>CLIMWATADAPT project</u>, develop an integrated framework to assess adaptation measures for the European water sector. Client: European Commission.

2010: Consultant, academic consultancy service for Cordaid the Netherlands to integrate climate change adaptation to the organisation's programmes.

PUBLICATIONS

Summary: 10+ peer-reviewed scientific papers, 90+ citations, H index 4

- **Hoang, L.P.,** van Vliet, M.T., Kummu, M., Lauri, H., Koponen, J., Supit, I., Leemans, R., Kabat, P. and Ludwig, F., 2019. The Mekong's future flows under multiple drivers: How climate change, hydropower developments and irrigation expansions drive hydrological changes. Science of the total environment, 649, pp.601-609.
- **Hoang, L. P.**, Biesbroek, R., Kummu, M., van Vliet, M. T., Leemans, R., Kabat, P., & Ludwig, F. 2018. Managing flood risks in the Mekong Delta: How to address emerging challenges under climate change and socioeconomic developments. *Ambio*, 1-15
- **Hoang, L. P.,** et al. 2016 *Mekong River flow and hydrological extremes under climate change*, Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci., 20, 3027-3041, doi:10.5194/hess-20-3027-2016, 2016
- **Hoang L. P.** et al. 2019 A power-smart social resilience analysis of flood interventions in the delta: The case of An Giang province, Vietnamese Mekong Delta. Project final report. Wageningen University.
- Nyadzi, E., Werners, E.S., Biesbroek, R., **Long, P.H.**, Franssen, W. and Ludwig, F., 2019. Verification of Seasonal Climate Forecast toward Hydroclimatic Information Needs of Rice Farmers in Northern Ghana. Weather, Climate, and Society, 11(1), pp.127-142.
- Nyadzi, E., Nyamekye, A.B., Werners, S.E., Biesbroek, R.G., Dewulf, A., Van Slobbe, E., **Long, H.P.**, Termeer, C.J. and Ludwig, F., 2018. Diagnosing the potential of hydro-climatic information services to support rice farming in northern Ghana. NJAS-Wageningen Journal of Life Sciences, 86, pp.51-63.
- Anh, D.T., **Hoang, L.P.**, Bui, M.D. and Rutschmann, P., 2018. Modelling seasonal flows alteration in the Vietnamese Mekong Delta under upstream discharge changes, rainfall changes and sea level rise. International Journal of River Basin Management, pp.1-15.
- Tran Anh, D., **Hoang, L.**, Bui, M. and Rutschmann, P., 2018. Simulating future flows and salinity intrusion using combined one-and two-dimensional hydrodynamic modelling—the case of Hau River, Vietnamese Mekong delta. Water, 10(7), p.897.

- Tran, D.D., Van Halsema, G., Hellegers, P.J., **Hoang, L.P.**, Tran, T.Q., Kummu, M. and Ludwig, F., 2018. Assessing impacts of dike construction on the flood dynamics of the Mekong Delta. Hydrology & Earth System Sciences, 22(3).
- Dewulf, A.R.P.J., Karpouzoglou, T.D., Warner, J.F., **Hoang, P.L.**, Thanh, B.N., Ahmed, F., Wesselink, A., Vos, J.M.C., Mao, F., Buytaert, W. and Tamas, P.A., 2018. Power-sensitive resilience in flood-prone deltas. Project final report, Wageningen University.
- Phan, T.H.D., Brouwer, R., **Hoang, L.P.** and Davidson, M.D., 2018. Do payments for forest ecosystem services generate double dividends? An integrated impact assessment of Vietnam's PES program. PloS one, 13(8)
- Phan, T.H.D., Brouwer, R., Davidson, M.D., **Hoang, P.L.**, 2017. A comparative study of transaction costs of payments for forest ecosystem services in Vietnam. Forest Policy and Economics, 80, pp.141-149
- The Mekong Delta Plan consortium 2012 Mekong Delta Plan: Long-term vision and strategy for a safe, prosperous and sustainable delta
- CESR, Alterra, CMCC, Ecologic 2011. CLIMWATADAPT Climate Adaptation modelling water scenarios and sectoral impacts, final project report to the European Commission
- Daniel, A.B., Granton, M.I., Ilja, K., Lisa, B., Hoang, P.L., van Berkum, S.W. 2010 Changing climate Changing Challenges: Identifying climate change impacts and integration of climate adaptation into Cordaid's programmes

GRANTS RECEIVED AND PARTICIPATION IN RESEARCH PROJECTS

2018: Wageningen University Research Grant (10.000 EUR) for strategic research theme on flood resilience.

2011-2013: Participate in the strategic, high-level collaboration between the Dutch and Vietnamese Government on developing the Mekong Delta Plan.

2018-2019: Research collaboration with NextBlue Foundation on the documentary project on living with water and climate change in the Mekong Delta (Me & Mekong).

2017-now: Participation in the international research project <u>EVOCA Responsible life-science</u> <u>innovations</u> for development in the digital age.

2016-now: Participation in the international research project <u>Waterapps</u> Water Information Services for Peri-urban Agriculture in Ghana and Bangladesh. Project funded by the Netherlands Organisation for Scientific Research.

SKILLS

Leadership: Lead components of various international research projects. Supervise M.Sc and PhD research projects. Actively participate in high-level international projects including the Mekong Delta Plan project and the ClimWatAdapt project for the European Commission. Establish New Amsterdam Consult, a start-up company operating in the Netherlands and Vietnam.

Communication: Experienced in cross-disciplines and cross-cultures communication. Competent with science-policy exchanges and communication.

Research: Implement research projects in hydrological modelling, water management and climate change. Experienced in advanced data analysis and visualisation (GIS), system analysis, climate change and socioeconomic scenarios developments

Education & Training: Provide lectures and teaching assistance in several courses at Wageningen University. Supervise Msc. and PhD researches.

Communication: Strong communication skills for (international) collaborations. Strong presentation skills including proposal pitching.

Scientific writing and publication: Advanced writing skills, experienced with publishing research articles in high-impact journals.

Languages:

Vietnamese (native)
English (full professional proficiency)
Dutch (Essential communication - level B1)

Programming: R (advanced user), C++ (basic user)

ADDITIONAL PROFESSIONAL INFORMATION

Major Accomplishments/Awards

2009 Anne van den Ban scholarship for international Msc students, Wageningen University, the Netherlands.

2013 Full Grant for PhD study, Wageningen University, the Netherlands.

Professional or Community Membership/Affiliation

Member of the European Geo-Science Union EGU

Member of the focus group for feedback and user experience for the <u>European Copernicus</u> <u>Climate Change Service</u>

Member of the <u>NextBlue</u> platform for citizen science and science-citizen-policy dialogues on water management and climate change.